[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：这就给我们带来了JavaScript，
&gt;&gt; Douglas: That brings us to JavaScript,
世界上最容易被误解的编程语言。
the world's most misunderstood programming language.
JavaScript拥有任何编程语言中最好的部分。
JavaScript has some of the best parts ever put into any programming language.
令人惊讶的是，这门语言的好的部分是多么的好，而且
That's extraordinary how good the good parts of this language are, and
我们将花费大量的时间来探索这一点。
we're going to spend a lot of time exploring that.
众所周知，JavaScript比任何其他编程语言都有更多不好的部分。
JavaScript also famously has more bad parts than any other programming language.
在接下来的一个小时里，我们将讨论为什么会发生这种情况，但它确实发生了，
And in the next hour, we'll talk about why that happened, but it does,
现在看来，每种编程语言都有好的部分和不好的部分。
now it turns out every programming language has good parts and bad parts.
但很少有语言像JavaScript或
But very few languages have as much goodness as JavaScript or
和JavaScript一样糟糕。
as much badness as JavaScript.
JavaScript拥有从崇高到完全荒谬的一切。
JavaScript has everything from the sublime to the completely ridiculous.
我将要做的分析，你可以在上面做
And the analysis I'm about to do, you could do on and
在每一种语言上都应该这样做。
should do on every language.
但在JavaScript中尤其具有说服力。
But it's especially telling with JavaScript.
所以因为JavaScript中有很多不好的部分，
So because JavaScript has so many bad parts in it,
我写了一个叫JSLint的程序。
I wrote a program called JSLint.
它是用JavaScript编写的，它读取JavaScript程序并警告您，
It's written in JavaScript it reads JavaScript programs and it warns you,
你在搅乱坏的部分。
you're messing with the bad parts.
通过清理并坚持好的部分，
And by cleaning that up and sticking to the good parts,
你最终会得到更好的程序。
you end up with programs which are substantially better.
更容易维护，更接近完美，这些都是好东西。
Which are gonna be more maintainable, closer to perfect, that's all good stuff.
而且它是免费的，每个人都应该使用它。
And it's free and everybody should be using it.
您的所有代码都应该无异常地通过JSLint，
All of your code should pass JSLint without exceptions,
你真的希望你的代码有那么好。
you really want your code to be that good.
但很多人不想这样做，因为它伴随着这个警告，
But a lot of people don't want to do that because it comes with this warning,
JSLint会伤害你的感情
JSLint will hurt your feelings.
这是真的，我听到人们不停地哭，抱怨，JSLint
And it's true, and I hear from people constantly crying, whining, JSLint
你把它修好，这样它就不会抱怨我了，因为我在那和之后都很棒
you fix it, so it doesn't complain about me because I'm awesome in that and after
几年后一个明星奇迹，嗯，等一下，在编程中没有哭泣。
a few years a star wonder, well, wait a minute, there's no crying in programming.
我们想象自己是世界上最理性的计算机
We imagine ourselves to be the most rational computers in the world or
世界上最理性的人，对吧？
that most rational people in the world, right?
因为我们是电脑的大使，你不能胡说八道，
Because we're the ambassadors to the computer, you can't bullshit computers,
我们想象自己对每件事都是完全合乎逻辑的
we imagine ourselves to be totally completely logical about everything
高于所有普通人。
superior to all ordinary mortals.
但事实证明，
But it turns out,
我们对事情非常情绪化，对于我们如何编写程序。
we get really emotional about things, about how we write our programs.
诸如制表符或空格之类的问题。
Questions like tabs or spaces.
事实证明并没有很多数据支持其中一种，但是
Turns out there's not a lot of data to support one versus the other, but
我们真的很情绪化，或者花括号在左边，或者
we get really emotional about it or do curly braces go on the left or
在右边？&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：你
on the right? &gt;&gt; Douglas: You
可以把这个问题扔到程序员的房间里，所有的工作都会停止。
can toss that question into a room with programmers and all work is gonna stop.
他们会有非常情绪化的争论，
And they're gonna have these really emotional arguments,
因为事实证明根本没有数据支持这两个论点。
because it turns out there is no data at all to support either argument.
没有数据表明你获得了更好的生产力或更低的错误率。
There's no data which shows you get better productivity or lower error rates.
任何重要的区别，但那并不重要。
Any important difference, but that doesn't matter.
争论将在那里，他们将是激烈的。
The arguments will be there and they'll be intense.
他们不会停止的。
And they won't stop.
为此，我责怪肯·汤普森。
And for this, I blame Ken Thompson.
肯·汤普森是有史以来最重要的程序员之一。
Ken Thompson is one of the most important programmers to have ever of lived.
我们稍后再谈他。
We'll talk more about him later.
他设计了一种叫做B的语言。
He designed a language called B.
它启发了被称为C的语言，
Which inspired the language called C,
从那时起，几乎所有的语言都受到了启发。
which inspired virtually all languages to happen since then.
非常重要的贡献。
Really, really important contributions.
在这些语言中，你可以把花括号放在左边或右边。
And in those languages, you could put the curly brace on the left or on the right.
汤普森把它们放在右边。
Thompson put them on the right.
只是在他看来是正确的，他的搭档Richie也把它们放在右边，但是
Just seemed right to him and his partner Richie also put them on the right but
他们的实验室里还有其他人，他们想把它们放在左边。
there are other people in their lab, who want to put them on the left.
我肯定他们开了个会，可能会持续几天
And I'm sure they had a meeting and it probably went on for days and
在某个时候，汤普森说，让我一个人呆着。
at some point, Thompson said, leave me alone.
我不在乎，只是，我不在乎。
I don't care, just, I don't care.
让我一个人呆着。
Leave me alone.
这是一个遗憾，因为他可以说，我正在修复我的编译器，所以
Which is a shame because he could have said, I'm fixing my compiler so
你必须把它们放在右边，如果你把它们放在左边，
that you have to put them on the right and if you put them on the left,
这将是一个语法错误。
it's gonna be a syntax error.
如果他这么做了，谁知道我们可以节省多少人-几个世纪的时间。
If he had done that, who knows how many man-centuries of time we could have saved.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH]
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：但他没有，所以
&gt;&gt; Douglas: But he didn't, so
我们还在争论这件事。
we are still arguing about it.
这是一个非常情绪化的争论。
And it's a really an emotional argument.
所以有些事情我们可以达成一致。
So there are some things that we can agree on.
每个人都会同意你应该始终如一，你应该总是把
Everyone would agree that you should be consistent, that you should always put
他们在左边或者你应该总是把他们放在右边，
them on the left or you should always put them on the right,
你不应该把它弄混，因为它看起来很蠢。
you shouldn't mix it up because it looks stupid.
我们真的很努力不让自己看起来很蠢，所以
We're trying really hard not to intentionally look stupid, so
你不会想这么做的。
you don't want to do that.
每个人都会同意，无论他们怎么做，其他人都应该这样做
And everyone will agree that however they do it, everyone else should do it that way
同样，这很容易，但我们无法就这种方式达成一致。
too, that it's easy, but we can't agree on what that way is.
所以如果你有一个习惯把它们放在左边的人，并且
So if you have someone who is used to putting them on the left, and
他去一家商店工作，把他们放在右边，然后再说一遍，
he goes to work for a shop that puts them on the right and again say,
我们就是这么做的。
well, that's how we do it.
得把它们放在右边。
Gotta put them on the right.
他会开始哭的。
He's gonna start to cry.
他说，不，他会开始想出理由
He goes, no, and he's gonna start trying to come up with reasons for
为什么这是错误的。
why this is wrong.
直觉告诉我们，这是错误的，第二个系统正在进行，是的，
And the gut is saying, this is wrong, this is wrong, and system two is going, yeah,
我知道这是错的，为什么？
I know that's wrong, why is that?
它开始合理化，
And it starts rationalizing,
它正试图找出理由来支持其根深蒂固的信念。
it's trying to come up with reasons to support its deeply held belief.
但是没有理由，所以，他听到你自己说的话
But there are no reasons and so, he hear yourself saying things which
完全是荒谬的，它只会让你更生气。
are completely ridiculous, and and it just makes you madder.
你越生气就越多，就是这样
And the madder you get the more, and it's just this and
最终没有任何意义。
it ultimately doesn't make any sense.
现在有点像开车。
Now it's sort of like driving.
在一些国家，他们靠左行驶，而且
In some countries they drive on the left, and
在一些国家，他们靠右行驶。
in some countries they drive on the right.
没有数据支持其中一种对另一种。
There's no data to support one versus the other.
你不会得到更好的燃油效率或者
You don't get better fuel efficiency or
降低一方或另一方的事故率。
lower accident rates on one side or the other.
但无论你在哪里
But wherever you are,
每个人都在同一边开车真是个好主意。
it's a really good idea that everybody be driving on the same side.
这个就是这样的。
And this is kind of like that.
我们知道应该有一个答案。
We know that there should be one answer.
想出一个答案真的很难，把它留给机会或者
coming up with the one answer is really hard and leaving it to chance or
任由个人品味决定并不能很好地预测任何类型的结果。
leaving it to personal taste is not a good predictor of any kind of outcome.
所以，我们可以继续在这上面浪费时间。
And so, we can keep wasting time on this.
所以最终
So ultimately,
除了JavaScript之外，我不知道这个问题的正确解决方案是什么。
I don't know what the correct solution to this is except in JavaScript.
在JavaScript中我绝对相信，
And in JavaScript I'm absolutely convinced,
你应该总是把它们放在右边，而不是左边，这就是为什么。
you should always put them on the right and never on the left, and here is why.
所以JavaScript最好的地方之一就是，
So one of the really nice things about JavaScript is,
我们可以有一个返回对象的函数。
we can have a function that returns an object.
有时您会调用这些构造函数。
Sometimes you call those constructors.
JavaScript提供了一个非常好的东西叫做Object literal，
And JavaScript provides this really nice thing called an object literal,
在那里我们可以返回一个新对象。
where we can return a new object.
非常好。
That's very, very nice.
如果你把花括号放在右边，它完全符合你的预期。
And if you put the curly brace on the right, it does exactly what you expect.
但是如果你把花括号放在左边，你会得到一个无声的错误。
But if you put the curly brace on the left, you get a silent error.
这些都是最糟糕的错误。
These are the worst kinds of errors.
编译时不会出现错误，运行时也不会出现错误。
You don't get an error at compiler time, you don't get an error at run time.
会发生的是你的函数而不是返回一个新的对象，
What'll happen is your function instead of returning a new object,
将返回未定义的值。
will return the undefined value.
所以它不会在这里失败，它会在这里下游的某个地方失败，
So it doesn't fail here, it's gonna fail somewhere downstream from here,
在那里有东西会去对一个物体进行操作，但它不在那里
where something will go to operate on an object, and it's not there and
程序爆炸了。
boom, program blows up.
所以，你必须调试这个东西。
And so, you're gonna have to debug this thing.
你可能最终会追溯到这条线。
And you may eventually trace it back to this line.
看起来是对的，我的物体去哪里了？
And that looks right, where did my object go?
你很容易在这上面浪费很多时间。
You can easily waste a lot of time on this.
所以让我们看看发生了什么，让我们放大这个。
So let's look at what happens, let's zoom in on this.
所以我们在接下来的一小时里会发现，
So as we're gonna find out in the next hour,
JavaScript是为初学者设计的一种语言。
JavaScript was designed as a language for beginners.
这就是最初的目标，就是成为初学者的编程语言。
That was the original goal, was to make a beginner's programming language.
但它看起来也像C
But it also looks like C.
而且C语言不是为初学者设计的。
And C was not designed for beginners.
C语法真的很模糊，它太复杂了。
C syntax is really fuzzy, it's way too complicated.
特别是如果你要把它给那些没受过太多训练的人。
Especially, if you're gonna give it to people who haven't had much training.
那你怎么处理这件事？
So how do you deal with that?
但我认为正确的答案是，
But I think the correct answer would be,
设计一种简单明了的新语法。
design a new syntax which is simple and clear.
不是他干的。
He didn't do that.
相反，有一个叫做自动分号插入的特性，
Instead, there was a feature called automatic semi-colon insertion,
其将尝试在某些位置插入分号，
which would attempt to insert semi-colons in places,
初学者不知道他们必须去那里。
where the beginners wouldn't know that they had to go.
不幸的是，它有时并不能把它们放在你认为它的地方
And unfortunately, it sometimes doesn't put them in places where you think it
应该，有时它会把它们放在你认为不应该的地方。
should, and it sometimes puts them in places where you think it shouldn't.
而这就是其中之一。
And this is one of those times.
因此自动插入分号将在返回后放置分号。
So automatic semicolon insertion will put a semicolon after that return.
现在我们有了所有其他的东西。
Now we've got all this other stuff.
你可能希望有些东西会遇到语法错误，所以
You would hope that something's gonna snag a syntax error, so
我们可以得到一些警告。
we can get some warning.
例如，我们有一个圆括号，它打开Object文字。
For example, we've got the curly brace which opens up the object literal.
除非您将花括号移动到语句位置，否则它将成为一个块。
Except when you move that curly brace into statement position, it becomes a block.
所以存在句法上的歧义。
So there's a syntactic ambiguity.
现在JavaScript没有块作用域。
Now JavaScript Doesn't have block scope.
因此，使用裸露的顶级块没有任何价值，但是
So there is no value in having naked top level blocks but
是的，所以掩盖了这个错误。
it does, so that masks this error.
然后我们有OK呼叫，OK冒号看起来不像是一个声明，但是
Then we've got ok calling, ok colon doesn't look like a statement but
看起来确实像个标签。
it does look like a label.
现在C语言中有一个GO TO语句，这意味着您可以
Now the C language had a go to statement in it, which meant that you could
将控制从一个语句转移到任何其他语句。
transfer control from one statement to any other statement.
而且我们已经确定goto是有害的，所以我们不再使用它了。
And we have since determined that goto is harmful, so we don't use it anymore.
它在JavaScript中不存在。
It does not exist in JavaScript.
JavaScript万岁。
Hurray for JavaScript.
在这方面它比C好。
It's better than C in that respect.
但是JavaScript语法仍然允许每个语句都有一个标签，
But JavaScript syntax still allows every statement to have a label,
即使只有四个语句有意义的标签。
even though there are only four statements that make sense having labels.
因为他们会利用标签中断
Because they'd make use of label break and
这不是其中之一，所以这是不好的。
that is not one of them, so that's bad.
虽然我们得到了一个虚假的陈述，
Although we've got a false statement,
虚假陈述没有任何意义，但还有另一个
of false statement doesn't make any sense, but there's another
我们从C继承的另一个东西是无用的表达式语句。
other thing we inherit from C which is the useless expression statement.
现在我们可以取任何表达式，把它放在语句位置，
Now we can take any expression, put it in statement position,
在它的末尾加上一个分号，现在它就是一个语句。
put a semicolon on the end of it, and it's now a statement.
在我看来，只有两种表达方式有意义
Now in my view, there are only two expressions that make sense
in语句位置、赋值和调用。
in statement position, assignment and invocation.
我认为，其他一切都应该是语法错误，但事实并非如此。
Everything else, I think, should be a syntax error, but it's not.
所以这在编译器中是允许的，看起来就会变假。
So this is allowed in the compiler will look at it go false.
然而你仍然是恒定的，很好，我只是继续。
Yet you're still constant, good, I'll just go on.
但如果它是一个语句，它需要一个分号。
But if it's a statement, it needs a semicolon.
我们的问题是我们有一些分号插入，所以它进来了
Our problem we've got some semicolon insertion, so it comes in and
插入那个。
inserts that.
现在块的末尾有一个分号，块不以分号结束。
Now there's a semicolon at the end of the block, blocks do not end with semicolons.
但我们从C继承了另一个特性，
But there's another feature that we inherit from C,
也就是空的陈述。
which is the empty statement.
所以在你想要的任何地方，你都可以有额外的分号，它们都会被浸泡。
So anywhere you want, you can have extra semi-colons and they all get soaked up.
那么，所有这些都是不可达的代码。
Then, all of this is unreachable code.
你不可能在中断之后执行一些事情。
That you can't possibly execute something that comes after disruption.
但JavaScript可以接受这一点。
But JavaScript is okay with that.
它允许你想要的任何东西，在没有任何警告的情况下返回语句。
It allows anything you want, after return statement without any warning.
所以如果你写的代码看起来像这样，
So if you write code that looks like that,
编译器认为您正在编写看起来像这样的代码。
the compiler thinks you're writing code that looks like that.
你可能会想，这是我见过的最愚蠢的事情。
You might be thinking, this is the stupidest thing I've ever seen.
你可能没说错。
And you're probably not wrong.
但它就是这样存在的。
But that's how it exists.
这就是这种愚蠢的语言所做的。
That's what this silly language does.
如果你把你的卷边括号放在右边，你将永远不会经历这种情况。
If you put your curly brace on the right, you will never experience this.
如果你把你的花括号放在左边，这就是在等你。
And if you put your curly braces on the left, this is waiting for you.
所以在考虑编程风格时，让我们看看这里的权衡。
So in thinking about programming style, let's look at the trade offs here.
那么，在一边放一个圆括号相对于另一边的成本是多少？
So what is the cost of putting a curly brace on one side versus the other?
零，没有成本，只是标点符号，没有成本。
Zero, there's no cost, it's just punctuation, there's no cost.
好处是什么？
What's the benefit?
好处是你永远不会在这个虫子上浪费时间，
The benefit is you will never waste time on this bug,
这个bug永远不会存在于你的程序中。
this bug will never exist in your program.
这是个好福利吗？
Is that a good benefit?
如果你能免费得到它，是的，绝对的。
If you can get it for free, yeah, absolutely.
这就是为什么在JavaScript中，我建议
So that's why in JavaScript, I recommend
总是把你的花括号放在左边或右边，不要放在左边。
always put your curly braces on the left or on the right, never on the left.
您应该更喜欢抗错误的表单。
You should prefer forms that are error resistant.
您应该以一种更难形成新错误的方式进行编码。
You should be coding in a way which makes it harder to form new errors.